Guide to the Amos Alonzo Stagg Papers 1866-1964
University of Chicago Library
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks, Notebooks, and Albums
  - Subseries 1: University of Chicago Athletic Scrapbooks
    - Athletic scrapbook No.36, June-September, 1904 - Includes 1904 Olympic Games at St. Louis, Olympic National Collegiate Championships, track, tennis, baseball, men’s and women’s golf, a new swimming pool at Bartlett Gym, football, changes in football regulations, and Amateur Athletics Union and professionalism. Also contains schedule for Women’s Athletic Association baseball and basketball games, wedding invitations and announcements, official score books, Junior Day souvenir programs, Interscholastic programs, telegrams, track meet programs, official program for World’s Fair and Louisiana Purchase Exposition, program of events for Olympic Games in St. Louis and interscholastic handicap meet, letters from Olympic officials, admission tickets for the World’s Fair and Exposition, schedule of football games, photo and postcards of football team, and football song sheet. (Box 145)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.37, October, 1904 - Includes football, players, recruiting from high schools and other universities, article on the endowment of college athletes by William Rainey Harper, improper inducements and accusations of football players, the Big Nine championships, and a wedding invitation. (Box 145)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.38, October-November, 1904 - Includes football, players, cross-country running, Big Nine championship, tensions with the University of Wisconsin and University of Michigan, postcards, wedding invitations, telegrams, and a letter to a football player. (Box 146)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.39, November-December, 1904 - Includes football, track, men’s and women’s swimming, possible hockey team, men’s basketball, cross-country running, new rules for athletic conference and a ban on freshman players. Also contains programs for football, Thanksgiving Day game, songs, announcements and programs for the second annual Order of the “C” banquet, telegrams, wedding invitations and announcements, football poem by Kathleen Martyn, get-well cards for Stagg, postcards, and a letter to previous “C” winners. (Box 146A)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.40, January-April, 1905 - Includes football in review, track, athletic reform, baseball, Eckersall and the Amateur Athletics Union, basketball, gymnastics, swimming and water polo, card with drawing and poem by Kathleen Martyn, postcards, track programs, first intercollegiate aquatic meet programs, invitations to musical events, gymnastic association program, telegram from Harper to Stagg, reports of the Athletic Committee of the North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, and New Year’s menu from Michigan hotel. (Box 147)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.41, May-July, 1905 - Includes track and field, Women’s Athletic Association, possible abolishment of the box office, tennis, interscholastic meets, and the Big Nine conference. Also contains program, tickets and schedule for Women’s Athletic Association in baseball, basketball, hockey, schedules for baseball an track, official letter from Stagg to Alumni to attend remaining baseball games, track programs, scorecards, Junior Day program, telegrams, wedding invitations, Chicago fight song, flyer for playlette “A Trick Play: A Comedietta in Three Acts” on football at the “Teatro D’Alonzo,” and June 4, 1905 sports pages of the Record Herald. (Box 147a)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.42, August-December, 1905 - Includes football, track championships in Portland, Oregon, restrictions on athletes and athletic clubs, 1906 Olympic Games Western Committee, Secretary of War W.H. Taft declares football is brutal, President Roosevelt asks for “anti-brutality” in the game, wedding invitations, and a flyer for “A Stag For Stagg” dinner and football reception for Stagg at the Reynolds Club. (Box 148)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.43, October, 1905 - Includes football, green suede postcard for Chicago v. Iowa game, invitation to consecration of Illinois Athletic Club, football programs with photos of players, telegrams, menu for “football special,” and a memorial notice for a student. (Box 148)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.44, November, 1905 (1 Oversize Folder) - Includes football, team members, introduction of soccer to the University, basketball, football grafting, high school football, World Today magazine cover with illustration of Chicago football players, tinted photo of Stagg, and a flyer for special train schedule for the Chicago v. Illinois game (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 149)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.45, November, 1905 - Includes football and championship game with Michigan, high school championship, controversy over grafting, President Roosevelt calls for reform of football, colleges abolishing football, articles with photos of football practice, notice to alumni on sale of tickets for Michigan-Chicago game, color cartoon of two chickens, postcards, and photo of Minnesota team. (Box 149)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.46, December, 1905 - Includes University of Chicago football champions and breakdown of the game, soccer, admission fee problems, formation of a basketball league, demand for football reform, Western Olympic Committee, and Roosevelt’s commitment to changes in football. Also contains photos of 1905 Minnesota and Chicago football teams, postcards, fight songs, tickets to Teatro D’Alonzo “A Trick Play,” and notice of a mass football meeting. (Box 150)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.47, December 1905-January 1906 - Includes National Football Committee on new rules, Walter Eckersall leads a champion season, football regulations and reforms, soccer, track, Olympics to be held in Athens, water polo, and professionalism vs. amateurism. Also contains Martyn’s Maroon rhymes, wedding invitations, letters regarding a team dinner, a leaf and card from Mrs. W.R. Harper, photos of Minnesota football field, the 1905 University of Chicago football squad and team member Hugo Bezdek. (Box 150)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.48, January-February, 1906 - Includes death of President William Rainey Harper, memorial library to be built, national football reforms and threats of abolition, possible removal of the “professional” coach and suspension of football by some schools, students protest new reforms, coaches and alumni recruiting players, varsity track, soccer, swimming, announcement about new law firm of a former Chicago football player. (Box 151)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.49, February-April, 1906 - Includes varsity track, baseball, swimming, changes and reforms of football, new clock for Mitchell Tower, basketball, effects of football reforms, Chicago athlete James Lightbody to compete in 1906 Olympics in Athens, programs for Cook Country High School Athletic League, programs for swim meets, and wedding invitations. (Box 151)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.50, April-June, 1906 - Includes Olympics in Athens, royalty attends the games, parades for athletes, expedition to the Arctic Continent by former Chicago football player, Margery Bell breaks record for women’s baseball throws, football schedules, some schools drop football, tennis, track, baseball, swimming, and interscholastic high school track meets. Also contains track programs with handwritten results, baseball postcards, flyer for Michigan v. Chicago in track and Chicago v. Amherst in baseball, and telegrams. (Box 152)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.51,June-October, 1906 - Includes track, football schedules and reforms, Olympics results, interscholastic high school meets, Hyde Park High School tennis, Chicago tennis, swimming, soccer, and implementation of new football rules. Also contains wedding invitations, Junior Promenade dance card, Order of the “C” banquet and menu, Junior Day programs and ticket stubs, telegrams, women’s athletics award ceremony for baseball, basketball, hockey and gymnastics, Reynolds Club dance card, programs for Cook Country High School Athletic League, programs for YMCA championship games in aquatics, gymnastics, athletics, an basketball, and official program for Central Association Amateur Athletics Union track championship. (Box 152)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.52, October, 1906 - Includes football, “Shakespeare and the fans” quotations from Shakespeare used to describe football games, official use of new rules, basketball, Russian baron ambassador and family cheers for Chicago, soccer, success of new football rules, 1906 football schedule, scorecard with player statistics, Collier’s article on “The New Football” by Walter Camp, and wedding invitations. (Box 153)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.53, October-November, 1906 - Includes varsity football, interpretation of new rules, debate over the training table, basketball, and big game with Minnesota, wedding invitations, and schedule of 1906 games. (Box 153)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.54, November, 1906 - Includes varsity football, players, Eckersall’s last game, former players and professional football coaches attempt to buy Stagg’s plays, football fatalities and new game rules, and article by Walter Camp on the final stage of the football season. (Box 154)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.55, November-December, 1906 - Includes football with reviews of rules and policies, Big Nine reforms the rules, other alterations of football and reversal of rules, track, basketball, swimming, hockey, Eckersall, student members dismissed from athletic board in favor of alumni, and the 1908 Olympics to be held in London. (Box 154)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.56, January-February, 1907 - Includes track, high school football, Big Nine discuss reforms, varsity baseball, wrestling, gymnastics, alteration of football rules, basketball, the “Big Four,” swimming, possible withdrawal of Michigan from Big Nine, 1908 Olympics to be held in London, sprint v. skate competition, baseball in Waseda University in Japan, flyer for gymnastic try-outs and double attraction of baseball and swim meets, and track programs. (Box 155)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.57, February-April, 1907 - Includes varsity baseball, track, swimming, basketball, high school athletics, gymnastics, Michigan and the Big Nine, telegrams, football cheers, flyer for indoor athletics, wedding invitations, track and Central Association of Amateur Athletics programs, swim meet programs, and program for championship gymnastics meet. (Box 155)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.58, April-May, 1907 - Includes varsity baseball, track, boycott of Michigan, tennis, problems with the Big Nine, problems with spectators, track and baseball schedules with photos of team captains, announcement of Williams v. Chicago baseball game, Amateur Athletics Union gymnastic championships, track and high school track programs, cards from the Athens Olympic Committee, official program for 1907 athletic season with photos of team members, postcards, rules for winners of the “C” and statement of purpose and constitution. (Box 156)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.59, June-September, 1907 - Includes Interscholastic high school track meets, golf, tennis, track, Eckersall becomes a sportswriter, article on the merits of the University of Chicago as a college, summer courses in football, the development of the forward pass, and vegetarian football players. Also contains wedding invitations, track programs, flyer and ticket stubs for interscholastic track, Junior Day program, University of Chicago annual vaudeville, football songs, and cartoons on vegetarian football players. (Box 156)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.60, September-October, 1907 - Includes football and high school football, rules and regulations of football, “Fletcherism” and vegetarian football players, and wedding invitations. (Box 157)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.61, October-November, 1907 - Includes varsity football, descriptions of the new rules, football championships, telegrams, and articles by Eckersall. (Box 157)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.62, November, 1907 - Includes varsity football, questions about football reforms and rules, basketball, small pox epidemic amongst the team, high school athletics, souvenir football programs, and typed Carlisle v. Chicago line-up schedule. (Box 158)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.63, November-December, 1907 - Includes varsity football, Big Nine plans for 1908 season, Olympic team committee, quarterback Walter Steffen signs contract with faculty to remain at the University of Chicago until he graduates, varsity track, basketball, swimming, Olympic trials to be held in Chicago, purity in football, development of the forward pass, summer baseball, benefits of a vegetarian diet. Also contains wedding invitations, a breakdown of summer baseball v. amateurism, and Olympic committee President J.E. Sullivan’s address to the annual meeting to the Amateur Athletic Union. (Box 158)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.64, January-February, 1908 - Includes western conference football rules, varsity swimming, track, Nebraska admitted to the Big Nine, the forward pass, basketball, baseball, and possibility of a crew team, potential Olympic athletes, and track programs. (Box 159)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.65, March-May, 1908 - Includes varsity track, baseball, limitations on football games, Dr. Meylan’s “tobacco virtues as health food,” swimming, basketball, coeds demand new swimming pool and gymnasium, Olympic try-outs at Marshall Field, wrestler George Hackenschmidt, and Chicago football player organizes and leads a protest for aid to hungry and jobless Bulgarians in Chicago. Also contains photos of Utah Agricultural College 1908 basketball team, track programs, high school track programs, wedding invitations, and University of Pennsylvania racing rules. (Box 159)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.66, May-June, 1908 - Includes varsity track, baseball, athletes train and attend trials for London Olympics, new athletic field, interscholastic high school track, tennis, Junior Day programs, banquet and menu for winners of the “C,” cards from general secretary of 1906 Athens Olympics, baseball and track schedules, photos of baseball and track captains, track programs, Official Olympic Program at Marshall Field, wedding invitations and announcements, entries for intercollegiate conference track meet, and programs and invitations for the dedication of the Alice Freeman Palmer Chimes. (Box 160)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.67, July 1908 - Includes 1908 Olympics in London, newspaper photos of athletes and events, the stadium, Amateur Athletics Association games in London, articles on athletes to compete in Olympic Games, list of events for games (with track and field, swimming, fencing, tennis, cycling, shooting, archery, and crew), ancient Olympic Games, British royalty at the games, medals, awards and prizes for athletes, and schedule for a conference track meet. (Box 160)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.68, July, 1908 - Includes 1908 Olympics in London, women’s gymnastic exhibition at the Olympic stadium, results of events, Stagg’s description of athlete’s voyage to games, American and French criticisms of the game and of British officials. (Box 161)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.69, July, 1908 - Includes 1908 Olympics, articles on athletes and the stadium, results of the games, the Queen presenting prizes to winners, Theodore Roosevelt’s response to the games, athletic cheers, and invitation from the American Ambassador to American athletes. (Box 161)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.70, July-September, 1908 - Includes 1908 Olympic results and awards, British accused of unfair practices during the games, famous yachtsman Sir Thomas Lipton entertains American winners, homecoming parade for U.S. athletes, Olympians to run in a final meet held by the Central Amateur Athletic Union, University of Chicago tennis, oxygen treatment for football players, accusations of professionalism, Caspar Whitney’s coverage of Olympics, wedding invitations, Gustavus T. Kirby’s response to criticism of Olympics, and the controversy over Olympics. (Box 162)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.71, September-October, 1908 - Includes football, using oxygen tanks with training, the first electric light practice, wedding invitations, and tickets to Iowa v. Chicago in football. (Box 162)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.72, October-November, 1908 - Includes football Chicago v. Minnesota, pre-game practices, team problems and weaknesses, and highlights of the game. (Box 163)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.73, November, 1908 - Includes varsity football, new plays, scouting other football teams, fight songs, game notes, handwritten letter from President Henry Pratt Judson, Cornell v. Chicago souvenir football program, and the University of Chicago official program for 1908 football season. (Box 163)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.74, November-December, 1908 - Includes football reforms, demonstration and mock “funeral” held by co-eds for their gymnasium, track, plans for 1909 football season, coverage on All-American quarterback Walter Steffen, Albert Spalding to donate a baseball library and the George Write and Henry Chadwick Collections of trophies, documents, and history of baseball. Also contains a flyer for special limited train for Chicago-Wisconsin game, Cornell v. Pennsylvania football ticket stub, cartoons, wedding invitations, and the official football program of Carlisle Indians v. Denver University. (Box 164)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.75, December 1908-January, 1909 - Includes varsity track, baseball, basketball, Stagg to referee a Denver University football game, the Chicago White Sox, Walter Camp’s All-Americans, summer baseball and the debate over amateurism, tennis, physical culture, gyms, and the lives of previous Chicago football stars. Also contains letter of resolution that eastern men embody all the athletic graces, drawings, tickets, invitations to Women’s Athletic Association’s “last rites” for their gym, Caspar Whitney’s All-American football team, wedding invitations, and programs for the 15th annual athletic carnival. (Box 164)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.76, February-April, 1909 - Includes varsity track, baseball, the University of Michigan and the “Big Eight” conference, swimming, 1909 football season, high school athletics, and the alteration of football rules. Also holds programs for swimming, track, Chicago Athletic Association, and freshmen meets, souvenir 1909 program, handwritten advertisement for a training table at the University of Illinois, a magazine page with a photo of the Denver basketball and football teams. (Box 165)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.77, April-June, 1909 - Includes track, high school athletics, first annual Illinois day, women’s field hockey, coverage of an Arctic expedition led by former Chicago athlete, “how to play first base,” flyers and programs for “Illinois Day” and “Purdue Day,” card from an Illinois representative about track, schedules for track and baseball, track programs for Chicago freshmen v. other first year students. (Box 165)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.78, June-September - Includes varsity track, interscholastic sports, varsity tennis, football, basketball, the “College Girl in Athletics,” and the largest stadium to be built in Tacoma. Also contains post cards, list of entries for Intercollegiate Conference meet and the winners, banquet menus, souvenir athletic problem, entertainment program for interscholastic meet, and wedding invitations. (Box 166)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.79, September-October, 1909 - Includes football, Walter Eckersall’s “How to Play Football,” Chicago roots and songs, football dates for the “Big Eight” with pictures of the captains, wedding invitations, and a souvenir football program. (Box 166)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.80, October-November, 1909 - Includes varsity football, Chicago plays Northwestern after three-year absence, University of Chicago football schedule, songs and cheers, and a wedding invitation. (Box 167)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.81, November, 1909 - Includes varsity football, baseball clubs, the Chicago White Sox, the Chicago Cubs, basketball, rugby, Amateur Athletic Union officials, Chicago faculty demands reforms in football, Woodrow Wilson of Princeton favors football, new ideas on changes in the game, and Cornell University sideline passes. (Box 167)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.82, November-December, 1909 - Includes varsity football, demands for regulation changes, Stagg to referee at Arkansas-Washington game, Woodrow Wilson wants to reform the game, varsity basketball, cross-country running, swimming, problems with Michigan and the Big 8 conference, rugby, and programs for 1909 Arkansas and Washington University in St. Louis teams. (Box 168)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.83, December 1909-February, 1910 - Includes football, rugby, reforms of football rules, Michigan and the Big 8 conference, varsity baseball, track, soccer, tackling, ice hockey, basketball, swimming, cross-country running, and wrestling. Also contains souvenir programs, wedding invitations, and program for First Regiment Athletic Carnival. (Box 168)
    - Athletic scrapbook No.84, February-April, 1910 - Includes varsity track, baseball, football reforms, high school athletics, basketball, swimming, Japanese baseball, Arkansas tries out new football rules, controversy over the forward pass, and Stagg teaches the “new” football. Also contains program for the Omaha Athletic Association Indoor Track Championships, wedding invitations, programs for swimming, track, athletic carnivals and track meets for Cook Country high schools. (Box 169)
    - Athletic Scrapbook No.85, April-June, 1910 - Includes varsity baseball, track, gymnastics, rugby, to Japan to play Waseda University in baseball in 1911, new football rules, problems with the forward pass, and coverage of soccer. Also contains track and baseball programs and schedules, programs for a gymnastics, wrestling and fencing tryout, wedding invitations and announcements, and passes and programs for University of Pennsylvania relay races. (Box 169)
    - Athletic Scrapbook No.86, June-September, 1910 - Contains track, interscholastic high school track meets and tennis tournaments, articles on why America loves athletics, the secret of success for Roosevelt and Stagg is exercise, University of Chicago tennis, “safer and saner football,” Chinese students compete in Mid-Western Chinese Student’s Conference track meet, football, and a Chicago swimmer attempts to swim the Mississippi River for world’s record. Also contains wedding invitations, programs for the interscholastic track and field games, contestant’s badges, and notes for the interscholastic games. (Box 170)
    - Athletic Scrapbook No.87, September-October, 1910 - Contains varsity football, revision of game rules, soccer, hockey, Keio University in Japan playing baseball, and wedding invitations. (Box 170)
    - Athletic Scrapbook No. 88, October, 1910 - Includes football, new intercollegiate football rules, Japanese baseball, soccer, and football programs. (Box 171)
    - Athletic Scrapbook No.89, November, 1910 - Includes varsity football and new plays, soccer, the Yearly Buffoon (a school paper complete with satirical editorials, advertisements, cheers, and an advice column to the lovelorn), the Leigh High Valley Railroad Dining Car Menu, official football program for Cornell v. Chicago, and highlights of Waseda University and Chicago’ s baseball game. (Box 171)
    - Athletic Scrapbook No.90, November-December, 1910 - Includes football, players and coaches, ice hockey at Chicago, Michigan and the Big Eight conference controversy, more coverage of Chicago playing baseball in Japan, varsity basketball, soccer, rugby, track and swimming dates, a track program, and the debate over the use of a training table. (Box 172)